SHANAKA SENEVIRATHNE

SOFTWARE ENGINEER - IOS

Unit 35, 1 Meryll Avenue, Baulkham Hill, 2153, New South Wales, Australia +61(0)414 673 400| shanaka36@gmail.com | www.shanaka.info

PROFILE

An articulate, confident and result oriented Software Engineer with over 7 years of professional industry experience. Always makes it a point to create software with the user in mind, creating applications with a useable and intuitive user interface experience. Understands the importance of creating highly readable and easily maintainable source code, along with constantly striving to learn new technologies and is a self improving person in this rapidly evolving industry.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

iOS Software Engineer - 3D Safety, Australia

Oct 2016 - Present

Working with internal company team to design and develop 3D Safety iOS mobile applications. Implementing user facing features in collaboration with backend we service developers. Incorporate mobile application with REST web services using ISON

Lead Mobile Software Engineer - Holition, United Kingdom

2014 - Sep 2016

Working with internal UX/UI designers to design and develop iOS and Android augmented reality, virtual reality and mixed reality applications. Mentoring junior software engineers as well as overseeing development of multiple software projects. Some of these applications are delivered to worlds top brands in cosmetics such as Hema, Mary Kay, Sally Hansen, Rimmel and Alexander McQueen.

Mobile Software Engineer - Holition, United Kingdom

2012 - Dec 2014

Working with internal company team to design and develop iOS and Android augmented reality applications. These apps range from internal company demos to fully deployed apps for clients. Some of these applications are delivered to worlds top retail brands such as Marks & Spencer, Hugo Boss, Platinum Guild International, Georg Jensen, Dunhill, Peninsula hotel Hong Kong, Vans, Uniqlo, Atelier Mayer, Hemyca, Abu Dhabi international airport, London college of fashion, Moet and Giorgio Armani.

iOS Software Engineer - Nextgen apps / Gamecell studios, United Kingdom

2011- May 2012

Working as a senior developer, design and develop iOS native apps that get deployed to apple app store. Working as the sole developer on an iOS / Android game that is live on apple app store.

Software Engineer - Sheffield Hallam University, United Kingdom

2009 - Feb 2011

Working with sports engineering team of Sheffield Hallam University to design and develop exer-games and other interactive applications on freelance basis. Some of these applications are delivered to clients such as: UK Sport, British swimming and Museums Sheffield.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

OS/Platforms : iOS, Mac OS X , Android, Windows, Linux, DOS, PlayStation 2

Programming Languages : Objective-C (2 years), C# (4 years), C/C++ (2 years), Swift, Java, Action Script 3.0, HLSL, Javascript, JSP,

Servelets, JSON, XML, HTML, CSS, SQL, PHP, Python

Libraries/APIs : iOS SDK, Core Data framework, .Net framework, Unity 3D engine, DirectX, Ogre 3D engine, XNA, STL, CEGUI,

OIS, Posix Threads, BSD Sockets

Development Environments : Xcode, Instruments, Mono Develop, Visual Studio, Android Studio, Eclipse, NetBeans

Applications/Tools : Git, Mercurial (Hg), Subversion (SVN), Unreal Development Kit, Nvidia PerfHUD, LAMP, 3ds Max, Blender 3d,

Photoshop, Flash Professional, Flash Builder

Databases : MSSQL, MySQL, SQLite, MS Access, Realm

Project Management : Developed the final year BSc. project on Agile software development, Agile, SCRUM, Waterfall, Jira

^{*} Please refer to the Completed Projects section for further information on projects that I have worked on

SHANAKA SENEVIRATHNE PAGE 2

ACHIEVEMENTS

Winner of Ideas4Innovation new researchers award sponsored by UK Sport.

Gold award for Best overall research paper at Sri Lanka Institute of Information Technology (SLIIT) Research

Symposium 2010

PROFESSIONAL CERTIFICATIONS

Sun Certified Java Programmer (SCJP) for the Java 2 platform 1.4

July 2007

2009

DISTANCE LEARNING CERTIFICATIONS

 $Fundamentals\ of\ Digital\ Image\ and\ Video\ Processing,\ Northwestern\ University$

June 2015

(https://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/verify/5QZ83GXZZ3)

Introduction to Mathematical Thinking, Stanford University

April 2015

COMPLETED PROJECTS

Face by Holition, Alexander McQueen - LCF, Sally Hansen ManiMatch, Rimmel London - Get the look

These projects are iOS and Android virtual try on cosmetics applications, which enable users to try on virtual makeup and nail polish using their mobile devices. Some of these applications are on app store and some are for bespoke installations and were used to highlight particular iconic looks and makeup of particular brands. Sally Hansen ManiMatch is world's first ever virtual try-on for nail colors in real time. Rimmel London - Get the look app is the first-ever personalised augmented reality mirror, which lets you try out make-up styles from pages of your favourite magazine.

Platform — iOS

Languages — C#, Objective-C, C++

Libraries — iOS SDK / Unity 3D engine

VANS, Uniqlo, Art of digital, Uniqlo Polo, Bicqlo, Moet, Moet Queens

These projects are iOS native applications, which communicated over wireless network to a master PC that had augmented reality software running. Essentially these iOS apps were used as controllers to control the main application. Much of these app used customized email as well as social media integration to share picture and videos.

Platform - iOS

Languages — Objective-C

Libraries — iOS SDK

Marks & Spencer Home, Hugo Boss watch collection, Platinum Guild, Georg Jensen Fusion, Dunhill, Atelier Mayer, Hemyca, Moscow iCube, London college of fashion, Giorgio Armani

These projects are iOS applications, which showcase a specific product or products with the help of Augmented Reality technology. Some applications among these included educational materials such as videos to encourage users to learn more about the brand and the product.

Platform - iOS

Languages — C#, Objective-C

Libraries — iOS SDK / Unity 3D engine

Peninsula hotel Hong Kong

'Peninsula' is an iOS and Android virtual reality / augmented reality application that allows the user to navigate and interact with a life size Peninsula hotel suite from their tablet devices. This app was created as a means for the customer to trial and walk about the hotel suite and get a feel for the size and sophistication of the suite. This app consists of high end graphics and in most cases is pushing the limits of the specific mobile platform it targeted.

Platform - iOS / Android

Languages — C#, Objective-C

Libraries — iOS SDK / Android SDK / Unity 3D engine

Abu Dhabi international airport midfield terminal

This is an iOS augmented reality application that allows the user to navigate and interact with a scaled down version of Abu Dhabi international airport new terminal from their iOS devices. This app was created as a means for potential duty free store owners to trial and walk about the new airport terminal and get a feel for the size and sophistication of the airport as well as passenger flow.

Platform - iOS

Languages — C#, Objective-C

Libraries — iOS SDK / Unity 3D engine

Rollie

'Rollie' is an iOS and Android gravity changing 2d platformer game with amazing visuals and fast phased game play. This Unity 3D project which is fully programmed in C#, consist of 60 unique levels, lots of enemies and a few bonus levels. This runs as a universal app on iOS devices.

Platform — iOS / Android

Languages — C#, Python, Obj-C

Libraries — iOS SDK / Unity 3D engine

To-Do 360

This project was a iOS native to do list and a task manager. This universal app changes its UI on iPads to take advantage of the screen real estate. With features such as attaching images, audio recordings, setting alarms and making the tasks trigger when you go to a certain place.

Platform — iOS

Languages — Objective-C

Libraries — iOS SDK

SHANAKA SENEVIRATHNE PAGE 3

Dance Star

'Dance Star' is a multiplayer exer-game developed with Sheffield Hallam University Sports Engineering team for Museums Sheffield 'Sports Lab' exhibition. The objective of the game is to encourage physical activity and exercise among children. The users interact with the game through a special device called smart-floor which detects human motion through several load cells. The detected movement is then transformed into animation of in-game avatar(s) which mimic player activity.

Platform - Windows PC

Languages — C#, HLSL

Libraries — XNA Game Studio 3.5, .Net Framework

Environment Visualization Software for Olympics 2012

This project was funded through UK Sport's Ideas4Innovation program; where the objective is to acknowledge and harness outstanding research and innovation concepts for elite sport, generated by the UK's research community, to support the mission to London 2012 and beyond. Due to confidentiality of this project, any information related to its targeted sport, venue of the event or athletes cannot be disclosed until 2012.

Platform - Windows PC

Languages — C/C++, HLSL

Libraries — DirectX, Ogre 3D, STL, OIS, CEGUI, Hydrax, SkyX

Design an Athlete

'Design an Athlete' is a single player educational serious game developed with Sheffield Hallam University Sports Engineering team for Museums Sheffield 'Sports Lab' exhibition. The objective of the game is to educate users on what type of arms legs and muscles an athlete needs to successfully complete a chosen set of Olympic events. The users interact with the game through a 19 inch widescreen touch display.

Platform — Windows PC

Languages — Action Script 3.0

Development Environment — Flash CS5 Professional, Flash Builder

PUBLISHED APPS

More than 10 apps published to iOS and Android app stores

Please refer to the following link for a complete list 'www.shanaka.info/downloads.html'

PUBLICATIONS AND PAPERS

"Application of Serious Games to, Sport, Health and Exercise"

Guest speaker at the Sri Lanka Institute of Information Technology (SLIIT) Research Symposium 2010

2010

EDUCATION

Sheffield Hallam University, Howard Street, Sheffield.

MSc. Games Software Development (Merit)

2009

Modules: Linux and Distributed Technologies for Games, Graphics and Animation, Interaction Design, Architecture and Technologies for Entertainment Software, Special Techniques for Graphics and Animation, Management of Entertainment Software Projects, Integrated Development Project, Research-Based Product Development.

Sheffield Hallam University, Howard Street, Sheffield.

BSc (Hons) Information Technology (Software Engineering) (First Class)

2008

Modules: Application Architecture and Frameworks, Case Studies in Software Design and Practical project.

Sri Lanka Institute of Information Technology, Sri Lanka.

Diploma in Information Technology

2006 - 2008

Modules: Software Engineering, Programming Language Design Concepts, Project Design & Management, Foundation of Computer Science, Information Technology Project, Design & Analysis of Algorithms, Database Management System, System Programming and Design, Software Technology (Java, C++), Probability & Statistic and Economics, Computer graphics & Multimedia and Data Communications and Computer Networks.

Royal College Colombo, Sri Lanka.

Sri Lanka GCE Advance Level Physical Science Stream

2004 - 2005

Modules: Physics, Chemistry, English.

SPECIAL SKILLS AND COMPETENCIES

- ❖ Ability to liaise with all levels of staff, as an energetic team player.
- Have been exposed to working in highly pressurized environments.
- Ability to adapt to changing situations.
- Fast Learner.

OTHER INTERESTS

- I have conducted number of seminars and workshops on 3ds Max and Maya for students at Royal College, Sri Lanka.
- I have had the enthusiasm to develop software for a long-time and self-taught many tools and technologies that groomed me with necessary skills to do so.